Good afternoon everybody
大家下午好
Welcome
欢迎
Good to see you
很高兴见到你们
So today we're going to study an arcane area of computer systems known as floating point
今天要学习的是浮点数，它是计算机系统中比较难理解的内容
Which is the way that computer systems represent the real numbers
它是计算机系统内部表示实数的方法
So you're all familiar with decimal you know something like 3.14
你们都熟悉十进制，比方说 3.14
And there's a similar idea with binary numbers
二进制数也有类似的东西
Okay so what does a fractional binary number like 10111.01 represent and how does that work
那么像 10111.01 那样的二进制小数代表什么呢？它是如何使用的？
Well, it works just like the fractional decimal numbers that you used to
它就像你熟悉的十进制小数一样使用
So you have a... this case, it's a binary point
在二进制小数中有一个二进制小数点
And to the left of the binary point
在二进制小数点的左边
You have bit positions to representing powers-of-2
每一位代表 2 的正幂
So 2^0, 2^1, 2^2
所以左边的每一位分别代表 2^0，2^1，2^2
So 1/2... I'm sorry. 1, 2, 4 and so on
所以从小数点开始向左依次是 1，2，4 等等
And to the right of the binary point
在二进制小数点的右侧
You have 2^-1=1/2, 2^-2=1/4, 2^-3=1/8 and so on
存在 2^-1=1/2，2^-2=1/4，2^-3=1/8 等等
So we can represent the... any fractional binary number
所以我们可以使用这种标记法表示任何二进制小数
Using this notation where we sum each the bit at position k*2^k
我们对每个第 k 处的值乘 2^k 后求和
Ok so it's really works exactly the same way as with base 10, just with base 2
这与 10 进制完全相同，只是将基数变成了 2
So let's look at some of these values
那么让我们看看其中一些值
So 5 3/4 we would represent as 101.11
所以 5 3/4 会被表示为 101.11
So this is before, (1*2^1) plus 1 is 5
所以二进制小数点左边相加后是5
+1/2, +1/4
（右边）+1/2, +1/4
Ok so 2/4+1/4=3/4. so 5 3/4
2/4+1/4=3/4。最终结果 5 3/4
Ok so that's pretty simple
好的，这很简单
2 7/8 is 10.111 so that 10 is 2 of course
2 7/8 表示为 10.111。二进制中的 10 是十进制中的 2
And then .111 is 1/2,so 4/8, 1/4=2/8+1/8, okay so 7/8
然后 .111 是 1/2（4/8）+ 1/4（2/8）+ 1/8 = 7/8
And 1 7/16 would be 1.0111
1 7/16 将是 1.0111
So that the 1 to the left of the binary point is 1
这样二进制小数点左边的 1 就是 1
And then we have 1/4+1/8+1/16
然后有 1/4+1/8+1/16
So 1/4 is 4/16, 1/8 is 2/16 and 1/16,so you add those up you get 7/16
所以 1/4 是 4/16，1/8 是 2/16，还有 1/16，所以总和为 7/16
Okay now notice that for some of these numbers
好的，现在注意到其中一些数字
This bit pattern 101.11
这个位组合，101.11
If we shift it to the right to get 10.111
如果我们将数字向右移动，获得 10.111
We've divided by 2, right? So we've taken 5 3/4 and divided it by 2
就相当于用 5 3/4 除以2
And it works the other way too
反方向也同样适用
If you shift to the left you multiply. If you shift to the left by 1 you multiply by 1
如果将数字向左移动 1 位，则乘 2 一次
And these numbers that are all ones to the right of the of the binary point
而二进制小数点右边的数字
These are numbers that are just slightly less than 1
这些数字只比 1 小一点点
So well when we want to represent those
因此，当我们想要表示这些值的时候
We will sometimes refer to those numbers of that form is 1- ℇ
我们有时会以 1.0-ℇ 指代那些形式的数字
And ℇ just depends on how many bits you have to the right of the binary point
而 ℇ 取决于你在二进制小数点右边有多少位
So ℇ gets smaller the more,the more of those bits you have there, it gets closer to 1
因此，ℇ 变得越小，二进制数的值就越接近 1
And ℇ gets smaller the more of those bits you have
并且 ℇ 越小，二进制小数点右边的位就越多
Now there's limitations in this kind of representation
但是，这种表示法存在局限性
So first of all we can only represent rational numbers of the form x/2^k
首先，我们只能表示形如 x/2^k 的有理数
We can only represent numbers of that form exactly
可表示的数必须严格满足那种形式
Other numbers have to get have repeating bit representations that can't be represented
不满足上述形式的数需要循环重复位才能被准确表示
with a finite number of bits that we have in a computer system
由于现在计算机中的位数是有限的，所以需要循环重复位的数不能被准确表示
So for example things like a 1/3 is this repeating representation 1/5 and 1/10 or other examples of that
因此，例如 1/3 就是需要循环重复位才能被准确表示的数，1/5 和 1/10 也是
Now the other problem we have is that
现在我们遇到的另一个问题是
We can only...
我们只能……
There's only so many bits to the left and the right of the the binary point
二进制小数点的左侧和右侧只有那么多位
So we're kind of...
所以
If we move the binary point to the left
如果我们将二进制小数点左移
Then we don't have as many... We can't represent as many large numbers
那么，很多原本能表示的数值较大的数现在就不能被表示了
We can only represent small numbers
我们只能表示小一点的数字
But we have more precision to the right of the binary point
但是在二进制小数部分有更高的精度
So we can represent more fractional values
所以我们可以表示更多的小数值
Just the range of those values will be much smaller
只是总的取值范围会小得多
Similarly if we move the binary point to the right
同样，如果我们将二进制小数点向右移动
We'll have a larger range of values
我们将拥有更大的取值范围
But we won't build represent as many fractions
但我们不能表示同样多的小数
So there's this kind of trade-off and floating point is a representation
因此，选择浮点作为折中的表示方式
to try that enables us to move that basically to move that binary point to represent sort of as wide a range as possible
浮点主要通过移动二进制小数点来表示尽可能大的取值范围
with as much precision given the number of bits
兼顾尽可能高的精度
the finite number of bits that we have to work with
同时还要受到位数有限的制约
So that the float and floating point is this sort of shifting binary point. Right
因此，浮点就是这种移动的二进制小数点
This floating, the floating binary point
能够不断变换位置的二进制小数点
Now up until 1985
在 1985 年之前
A floating point was just a disaster
浮点数一直是一场灾难
And every computer manufacturer had their own representation
每个计算机制造商都有自己的实现方式
You couldn't...and it was just terrible,because you couldn't predict
它太可怕了，因为你无法预测会发什么
What would happen if you moved your program from one machine to another
如果你将程序换一台机器运行
The behavior would be different the rounding would be different
（程序的）行为会变得不同，舍入也会变得不同
It was a very difficult situation and people really, computer scientists in particular, really disliked floating point
这是一个非常糟糕的状况，人们特别是计算机科学家真的不喜欢浮点
In 1985 IEEE which is the professional association for electrical engineers
1985 年，电气电子工程师协会（IEEE）
Introduced a...and it's also a very important standards body
引入了一个非常重要的标准化表示
They introduced a standard floating-point representation called IEEE floating point
他们引入了一个称为 IEEE 浮点数的标准浮点数表示法
which was then adopted by all computer manufacturers
得到了所有计算机制造商的一致采用
So now the situation is much better
所以现在情况要好得多
Everybody supports the same kind of floating point representation
各方都支持相同类型的浮点数表示
which is what we're going to learn about today
这就是我们今天要学习的内容
So the floating point has the form
所以浮点数有如下形式
It represents numbers in a... this is, like a scientific notation
它以一种类似科学计数法的方式来表示数字
It represents numbers of the form (-1)^S*M*2^E,where S is a sign bit,times a significand M
它表示形式 (-1)^S*M*2^E 的数字，其中 S 是符号位，乘以尾数 M
Ok times 2^E
然后乘以 2 的 E 次幂
Ok so all of the numbers that we can represent in floating point have to be represented in this form
所有浮点数都必须以这种形式表示
So the sign bit S determines whether the number is negative or positive obviously
显然，符号位 S 确定了该数字是负数还是正数
The significand M and this is sometimes sometimes called the mantissa
尾数 M，有时叫做 mantissa
where the M comes from
单词的首字母就是 M 的来源
The significand M normally is a fractional value in the range between 1 and 2
尾数 M 通常是介于 1 和 2 之间的小数
And we'll see why that is in a second
接下来，我们会很快看到这样设置的原因
And then the exponent E weights the value by some power of 2
指数 E 会以 2 的 E 次幂形式扩大或或缩小尾数值
Okay so this is encoded in either 32-bit or 64-bit
32 位或 64 位编码中都是这样
In the following way the the sign bit S is the most significant bit
下面的表示中，符号位 S 是最重要的位
And then this is followed by some number of
紧随其后的
by some number of bits called the exp field
是一些被称为指数（exp）域的位（阶码）
which encodes the exponent E
它编码了 E
But it's not identical to E,it encodes E, we'll see how that works
但编码表示的值与 E的值不同，它只是编码了 E ，我们会看到它是如何起效的
And then the frac. And then that's followed the remaining bits are the the frac field
后面剩下的比特位是尾数（frac）域
which encodes M but isn't identical to M
它编码了 M 但与 M 不完全相同
Now we are...IEEE floating point has provides two different kinds of floating-point
IEEE 提供了两种不同的浮点数
The single precision 32 bits and so-called double precision which is 64 bits
单精度 32 位和双精度 64 位
There's this funky intel extended precision
还有这种特别的英特尔扩展精度
which is non-standard and we won't talk about it anymore
由于这是非标准的，我们此处不再讨论
And so in the single precision 32 bits
在 32 位单精度浮点数中
You have one sign bit, there's always a sign bit
总有一个符号位
You have 8 exp bits and you have 23 frac bits
还有 8 个阶码位和 23 个尾数位
In double precision you have 11 exp and 52 frac bits
在双精度中，有 11 个阶码位和 52 个尾数位
Now there's a number of different kinds of floating-point representations
现在有许多不同类型的浮点表示方法
The sort of the default and sort of the common representation is called normalized
默认及通用的表示方法被称为规格化的（表示方法）
So called normalized values
也就是所谓的规格化值
And normalized values are
规格化值是指
All the values where the exp field is not equal to 0
其中阶码字段的所有位的值
And not equal to all zeros and not equal to all ones
不能全是 0 也不能全是 1
So everything all zeros and all ones are special kinds of numbers we'll look at a second
全 0 和全 1 的情形都是特殊类型的数字，稍后我们会讲到
So the exponent...this exponent E remember our numbers are (-1)^S*M*2^E
对于公式 (-1)^S*M*2^E 指数 E
The exponent E is encoded as this biased value which is the called exp
指数 E 被解释为以「偏置（biased）」形式表示
So the exponent E is exp-bias
所以指数 E 的实际值为 exp-bias
And exp is the value
而 Exp 的值是
Exp is the value of the exp bits, the bits in the exp field treated as a positive number
Exp 位的值，也就是把 exp 域的值（一直）作为一个正数
Okay so Exp, you just look at it as an unsigned 7-bit in case of single precision 7-bit number
所以在单精度 7 位数字的情况下，你只需将它看作 7 位的无符号整数
Okay now the Bias=2^(k-1)-1, where k is number of exponent bits
现在偏移值 Bias=2^(k-1)-1，其中 k 是阶码域的位数
Okay so for single precision we have 8 exponent bits
那么，对于单精度，我们有 8 个指数位
So 2^8... 2^(8-1=7) so 2^7=128-1 is 127
所以 2^(8-1)-1=2^7-1=128-1=127
Ok so the Bias for single precision is 127
所以单精度的偏移值是 127
And similarly for double precision it's 1023
同样，对于双精度，它是 1023
Okay so you just have to memorize this formula
所以你只需要记住这个公式
The exponent E is the exp field interpret it as an unsigned number minus the the bias
指数 E 的值是无符号 Exp 值减去偏置值 Bias
This is kind of a strange thing the first time you encounter floating-point
当第一次遇到浮点时
It seems kind of odd, right? So why not...
不免觉得这似乎有点奇怪，对吧
I mean we've already learned about two's complement
我的意思是，我们已经学会了二进制补码
That's a perfectly fine way to represent positive and negative numbers
这是表示正数和负数的完美方式
Okay we have exponents that are negative and positive, right
既然指数有负的也有正的
So why not just use the exp field to represent
那为什么不在 exp 域中使用二进制补码
Why not just use a two's complement in the exp field to represent those positive and negative exponents, right
来表示那些正的和负的指数呢
So it turns out that the reason that they do this is
事实证明，这样做的原因是
is that...
就是……
And if you think about this and we'll come back to it
你不妨考虑考虑这个问题，我们会回过头来讨论
But if we encode the the exponent E using this bias representation
但是如果我们使用这种偏置值的方式来编码指数 E
The smallest negative exponent is represented by all zeros
最小的负指数由全 0 表示
And the largest exponent is represented by 01...111
最大的指数由 01...111 表示
So the smallest, the number with the smallest exponent
所以最小的指数......
If we were just to compare the bits
为了比较二进制数
using a just some kind of unsigned representation, just comparing the bits, treating it as an unsigned number
只需要采用无符号表达，比较各个位，把它当做无符号整数
By using this biased representation
我们可以通过使用这种偏移值表示法
we can just compare two floating-point numbers just as unsigned
来比较两个浮点数，就像无符号整数一样
We can treat the whole floating-point number as an unsigned integer and compare two numbers
我们可以将整个浮点数视为无符号整数并比较这两个数字
And get a true comparison
就可以得到真正的比较
So the exponent uses this this sort of biasing encoding
所以指数使用这种偏置编码法
And then the significand is encoded with an implied one
尾数采用隐含编码法
So and this is where the... this is where the normalized
这就是
... and the normalized representation comes from
规格化表示的来源
That we're always going to represent our numbers
这是我们想表达数字的方法
So M... we're always going to normalize M
所以我们总是要将 M 规格化
no matter what the number we want to represent
无论我们想要表示什么数字
We're always going to normalize M as 1.xxx...x
我们总是将 M 规格化为 1.xxx...x
And then we adjust the exponent accordingly
我们相应地调整指数（来进行规格化）
So if the value we want to represent is 100.01
因此，如果我们想要表示的值是 100.01
We're going to shift it over and it will be 1.00
我们将把它的二进制小数点左移，使之成为 1.00
Okay and then we'll adjust the exponent to represent that shift
然后我们调整指数来表示这种位移
Okay so the bits in the frac field xxxx...x are
那么，尾数域 xxxx...x 中的位是
All of the numbers to the right of the binary point right
二进制点右边的所有数字
So there's always this implied one
这个1一直隐藏的
But we don't even encode it we just throw it away
我们甚至没有对它进行编码，我们只是扔掉它（不对这个1进行存储）
Because it's always there right
因为它总是在那里
So this is a little trick just to get it one more bit for free
所以这是一个小技巧，只是为了免费获得一位
Okay so the the xxx bits in the frac field
好吧，尾数域的 xxx 位
All the bits to the right of the binary point after one point the one point
二进制小数点之后的所有位在 1. 之后
And this is,the so this is the smallest fractal is all zeros
所以最小的尾数域全是 0
Which corresponds to a significand of 1.0
这相当于尾数是 1.0
A frac field of all ones corresponds to 2-ɛ
所有位都是 1 的 frac 对应于 2-ɛ
So that's 1.111...
那是 1.111......
So let's look at an example
那么让我们看一个例子
So let's look at how we would encode 15213 which our favorite number In two's complement in floating point
那么让我们来看看如何使用浮点数的方式来编码我们最喜欢的数字 15213
So the if we represent that so it's an integer
如果我们使用这种发式表达它，它就是一个整数
And we represent it using these bits take my word for it correspond to the integer 15213
我们使用这些位表示它，它对应于整数 15213
So now we want to convert it we want to normalize it
现在我们要转换它，我们想要标准化它
By expressing it as 1.110xxx * 2^13
通过将其表示为 1.110xxx*2^13
Okay same number we just normalized it
这是相同的数字，我们只是将其规格化了
So that there's always this leading 1
所以总是有这个开头的 1
So the significant m is 1.11011xxx
所以尾数 m 是 1.11011xxx
The frac field is everything to the right of the binary point
二进制小数点右侧的内容对应着尾数域
So we just,we throw this one away
所以我们可以把这个 1 忽略掉
And we just take the the values to the right of the binary point
我们只需取得二进制点的右侧的值
And then we pat it out with zeros to get the 23 bits that we need for single precision
然后我们用零来补全它以获得我们需要的单精度浮点数的 23 位
Ok so now we've got our frac field
好的，现在我们有了尾数域
The exponent
指数
So in this case right E is
所以在这种情况下，E 是
We're multiplying by 2 ^13.So E is 13
我们乘以 2^13， 所以 E 是 13
So we want to represent the value 13 using this bias encoding
因此，我们希望使用此偏置编码来表示值 13
So the bias is 127
所以偏置值是 127
And so the exponent the value...the value of the exp field should be 140
所以 exp 域的值应该是 140
Because if we take 140-127 we get 13
因为如果我们拿 140-127 就会得到 13
Okay so 140 is represented using these 8 bits
好的，所以使用这 8 位表示 140
And that becomes our exp field
这就成了我们的阶码字段
Okay so the resulting floating-point number
好的，所以得到的浮点数
And of course it's a positive number so the significand bit is zero
符号位为零，因此是一个正数
So the resulting floating point number has these eight
因此得到的浮点数有 8 位 exp
The 8 bits and exp field that we computed by subtracting 127 from 140
我们通过从 140 减去 127 来计算阶码的值
And then the frack field are these bits that we got here by just taking everything to the right of the binary point
我们将所有内容都放在二进制点右侧而得到的这些位就是小数字段
So this...
所以这...
So let's look at this exponent just a little bit more
让我们再看一下这个指数吧
Because I think can be a little confusing
因为我觉得可能有点令人困惑
So in our example
所以在我们的例子中
If we want to look at the range of Exp
如果我们想看看 Exp 的范围
So what's the smallest value of exp
那么 Exp 的最小值是多少
What's the smallest value of exp?
Exp 的最小值是多少？
Don't confuse the encoding with the value it represents
不要将编码值与它的实际值混淆
Exp is just the encoding
Exp 只是编码
So what's...  what's the smallest value of exp?
那么......exp 的最小值是什么？
0 that's right
0 那是对的
Okay and the largest value is? is what?
好的，最大的值是什么？
It's... what's the largest value?
这是......最大的值是什么？
Yes
是
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Well the largest value would be remember it can't be all ones
那么最大的值就是记住它不可能每个位全是 1
Right so the largest value would be 2^8-1
正确，因此最大值为 2^8-1
So okay so the largest value would be 01111...
好吧所以最大的值是1111....
（译者注：最大值为11111111，老师此处讲解错误）
0 followed by 7 ones
So that's a 2^8-1 is ...
那是 2^8-1 是......
255 good
Okay so then what's the range the of E
那么那么 E 的范围是什么呢？
Which is the actual value that we want to encode
也就是我们想要编码的实际值
Okay member use this we have this definition
我们有这个定义
So we have the range of values for exp
所以我们有 Exp 的值范围
We have our bias
我们有偏置值
So what is the range of values for E
那么 E 的值范围是多少？
This is the actual exponents that we're encoding
这是我们编码的实际指数
So what's the smallest exponent,-127 good
那么什么是最小的指数，-127，对
Right because that's zero is our smallest exp-bias which is -127
因为零是我们最小的 Exp-bias，即 -127
Okay so the smallest value of E is 127
好的，所以 E 的最小值是 127（应该是 -127）
And the largest value of E is ?
E的最大值是？
So if we take the largest value of exp that's 255-127=128
因此，如果我们取 Exp 的最大值为 255-127=128
Okay so the numbers that we can represent using this bias notation
好的，我们可以使用这种偏置表示法表示的数字
We have the smallest exponent will be 2^ -127
我们有最小的指数将是 -127
And the largest exponent will be 2 to the raised to the power 128
并且最大指数将是 128
Okay so you see what's going on here
好的，所以你看看这里发生了什么
So we have a range of values for E
所以我们有一系列的 E 值
Here's the largest value,here's the smallest value,here's 0 right in the middle
这是最大的值，这里是最小值，中间是 0
These are the values we want to represent this biasing is like a shift
这些是我们想要表示这种偏置的值
We've just now we're shifting up by 127
我们刚才将 E 的范围移动 127
So that now the smallest exponent is represented by 0
所以现在最小的指数用 0 表示
Okay any questions about that
好的，对此有任何疑问
Now these normalized values always have this implied one
现在这些规格化值尾数总是有一个隐含的 1
Okay which... when we want to represent numbers closer to zero
好的...当我们想要表示接近零的数字时
That limits us right
这（个隐含的 1 ）限制了我们
So there's another type of floating-point number called the denormalized value
所以还有另一种称为非规格化的浮点数
Which is characterized by an exp field of all 0
其特征在于 exp 域全为 0
And in a denormalized number or denorm there's no implied one
在非标准化值中，没有隐含的数字 1
Okay so the the significant m is represented exactly is encoded identically in the frac field
所以尾数 M 的值 frac 域编码值完全等价
So there's no implied one
所以没有隐藏的 1
And all of the numbers are the form zero point something something something after them
并且所有数字都是 0.xxx 形式的东西
And the exponent value E instead of you remember for denorms we subtracted bias from exp
并且指数值 E 不是规格化的值那样等于 Exp 减去偏置 bias
For denorm we subtract the bias from one
对于非规格化值，E=1-bias
Okay now if we just use the definition
好的，现在我们使用这个定义
We use for normalized numbers that would be...exp would be zero
我们使用的规格化数字将是...... exp 将为 0
So we don't do that instead
所以我们不这样做
E = 1 - bias
（非规格化数中）E=1-bias
And then the significant is coded with an implied leading 0 instead of a leading one like a mentioned
然后，符号用隐含的前导 0 编码，而不是如前所述的前导 1
So when exp is zero and also I mean
因此当 exp 为零时，我的意思是
We think about it. If we only had normalized numbers
我们考虑一下。如果我们只有规格化的值（老师口误，说成denormalized）
We wouldn't be able to represent zero right because there'd always be a 1 in there
我们无法代表零，因为总有一个隐含的 1
So the denorms allow us to represent zero
因此，这些非标准化的值使我们能够代表零
And they allow us to represent values that are very close to zero
它们允许我们表示非常接近零的值
So when the exponent is zero
所以当指数为零时
And the exp field is zero and the frac field is zero then this is the zero value
exp 字段为零，frac 为零，则为零值
And so this is nice because all zeros represents zero
所以这很好，因为全零代表零
Which is you know sort of which one
你知道哪一种
There is the sort of weird thing though that
尽管如此，有一种奇怪的东西
If you have a the sign bit is 1
如果你有一个符号位是 1
And then your frac and exp is 0 then you have -0
然后你的 frac 和 exp 为 0 然后你有 -0
So you have this kind of odd situation where there's a positive and negative zero
所以你有这种奇怪的情况，那里有正负零
Okay and other values if exp is zero and you have a nonzero frac
好吧和其他值，如果 exp 为零，你有一个非零小数
And those are the equally spaced numbers that are closest to zero
那些是最接近零的等间距数字
Now there's a couple of other special values
现在还有其他几个特殊的值
When exp is all ones and frac is all zeros
当 exp 为全 1 时，frac 全为 0
This represents the value infinity
这代表无穷大的值
So this is a value that that we get
这是当
When is some kind of addition or multiplication and we overflow
因为加法或乘法而且溢出时得到的值（无穷大）
So in floating point always overflows to the special value called infinity there positive or negative infinity
所以在浮点上总是溢出到称为无穷大的特殊值，有正或负无穷大
So it's different from two's complement right where
所以它与二进制补码的不同之处在于
You sort of overflowed into in this modular way back  just back it round into the range of numbers
你可以用这种模块化的方式回推，然后回到数字范围内
In floating point we just overflow to the sticky value called infinity and then everything we do on that remains infinity
在浮点数中，我们会溢出到称为无穷大，然后我们对其做任何操作结果仍然是无穷大
So for example if we did...
例如，如果我们做了......
If we did 1/0 or -1/-0 we'd get positive infinity
如果我们做了 1/0 或 -1/-0，我们就得到正无穷大
If we divide 1 by 0 negative 0 we get negative infinity
如果我们将 1/-0，我们得到负无穷大
The fourth kind of special case special number is the case where  the exponent again is all once but the frac is nonzero in a nonzero value
第四种特殊数字是指数全部是 1 但小数字段非零值的情况
And this represents what's called not a number so this is
这代表了非数字（NaN）的情况
This handles cases where there's no,there's no answer
这个值代表了没有答案的情况
There's no feasible answer for example if we you know try to take the square root of -1
例如，如果我们尝试取 -1 的平方根，就没有可行的答案
What we'll get back is not a number
我们得到的不是数字
So I think it's helpful to to visualize these the number line now so the
我认为将这些数字可视化是有帮助的
We have +0,-0 sort of right next to each other and then to the right of that are the positive denorms
我们有  0，-0 彼此相邻，然后在右边是正的非标准化值
And then those sort of transition into the normalized numbers
然后过渡到标准化数字
And then you have infinity positive infinity
然后你有正无穷大
You have a similar similar situation on the for the negative numbers
对于负数，你有类似的类似情况
And then negative and positive not a numbers
然后就分别是正数和负数情况下的非数字（NaN）
So I think the you know you've probably discovered
所以我想你知道你可能已经发现了
The really good way to try to understand these numeric and Coatings is just to do examples with only a few number of bits
举一个仅包含几位的例子是尝试理解这些数字和规则的有效方法
You know if you want to understand like for example in two's complement
你知道如果你想要理解，比如二进制补码
If you want to understand Tmin and Tmax and how they relate to each other
如果你想了解 Tmin 和 Tmax 以及它们之间的相互关系
Just do a three bit two's complement system
只做三位二进制补码系统
You know imagine just have a system with two's complement of three bits
你想象一下，系统有二进制三位补码
And then you can just enumerate all those all the possibilities and you can see
接着你可以枚举所有可能的情况
And then you see where you know the Tmin is actually one greater than Tmax
然后你会发现Tmin （的编码）实际上比 Tmax（的编码） 大一
You know so if you add one to Tmax it actually overflows into Tmin
如果将Tmax（的编码）加 1，就会溢出从而变成Tmin（的编码）
（译者注：3:011编码加一后变为-4:100）
Similar thing for floating point it's...I would really encourage you to do this
浮点数也有类似的事情......我真的很鼓励你们这样做
Just try some simple examples with a sort of tyent with a small number  of exp and frack bits
只需尝试一些带有少量 exp 和 frac 位的简单示例
So in this case we're going to look at a floating point system based on IEEE
所以在这种情况下，我们将看到一个基于 IEEE 的浮点系统
That has 4 exp bits and three frack bits
它有 4 个 exp 位和 3 个 frac 位
As always the sign bit is the most significant bit
符号位是最高有效位
Followed by exp followed by frac
其次是 exp，然后是 frac
Okay so this is identical to IEEE floating point except for the size of that  exp in fractals
除了exp，frac 的位数外，其他都与IEEE 浮点数标准完全相同
So it's actually small enough that we can now just enumerate these values
所以它实际上足够小，小到我们可以枚举这些值
And now you can, you can start to see why these weird definitions for the exponent in the denominator
现在你可以，你可以开始看到分母中指数的这些奇怪定义的原因
So let's just look at...
那么我们来看......
So we will stand here,we've just
我们只是
All of 2^7 possibilities possible combinations of exp and frac fields starting with zero
列出从零开始所有 2^7 种可能的 exp 和 frac 字段的组合
Okay so when exp is all zeros
好的，所以当 exp 全部为零时
That's a denorm right by definition
根据定义，这是一种非规格化值
And then we have the three frac bits are all zero
然后我们有三个小数字段位全零
Okay so remember the exp is all zeros
好的，所以记住 exp 全是零
Right so the for denorm the exponent value is 1- bias, bias here is 7
因此，对于非标准化数指数值是 1-bias，这里的 bias 是7（bias 即偏置值）
Okay so 1-7 gives us a value for the exponent of  -6
好的，1-7 得到指数值是 -6
So we're going to take the frac
接着我们要取得小数字段
The bits in the frac field times
frac 表示的值乘以 m
So m is 0
m 是 0
So m in this case is 0*2^-6 gives us 0
所以在这种情况下是 M 是 0，0*2^-6 得到 0
So this is our representation of 0
所以这是我们 0 的表达方式
And like I said it's really it's nice that it actually is
就像我说的那样，实际上真的很棒
If we just treated this as an unsigned integer, it would be 0
如果我们只是将其视为无符号整数，那么它表示 0
Okay so that's kind of pleasing
好的，这样很愉快
Now let's look at the very next number right
现在让我们看看下一个数字吧
The exp is still 0 and we've just bumped up frac by 1
exp 仍为 0，我们刚刚将 frac 加了 1
Ok so again it's a 1-bias which is -6
好的，依然 E=1-bias，即 -6
And now this,this frac field represents this is 1/2,1/4,1/8
现在这个，这个 frac 域各位依次表示 1/2, 1/4, 1/ 8
So it represents,so this is a value of amaz it is 1/8
所以是 1/8
So 1/8*2^-6(1/64)=1/512
所以 1/8*2^-6（1/64）= 1/512
So in this floating point system the smallest nonzero number
这个数是这个浮点数系统中最小的非零数
We can represent is the denormalized representation of 1/512
我们只能用非规格化表示 1/512
The next smallest number is 0
下一个最小的数字是 0
Okay now let's look at, so let's take, let's bump this up by one
好的，现在让我们来看看，让我们把它再增大 1
So now we get a frac field of 010
所以现在小数字段区域是 010
So this represents 1/4
所以这代表 1/4
So m is 1/4 that significant is 1/4*2^-6
所以 m 是 1/4，明显（结果）是 1/4*2^-6
So 2/8*1/64 is 2/512
所以 2/8*1/64 是 2/512
Okay so the the numbers were just it by incrementing this  by incrementing are significant
这些数字通过递增 frac（尾数）来不断递增是有意义的
We're increasing the numbers by 1/512
我们将这个数字增加了 1/512
Now the largest denorm in this number system is the case where the frac field is all ones
当frac 域全 1的时候，非规格化数取得最大值
And so this encodes 1/2+1/4+1/8 which is 7/8
所以这编码为1/2 + 1/4 + 1/8，即7/8
And then our value is 7/8*2^-6(1/64) =7/512
然后我们的值是 7/8*2^-6（1/64）= 7/512
So this 7/512 is the largest denormalized number we can represent in this system
所以这个 7/512 是我们在这个系统中可以表示的最大的非规格化的值
And now if we bump our number up by one the the frac field resets to zero
现在如果我们将数字增加 1，则 frac 重置为零
And now the exp field goes from 0 to 1
现在 exp 域从 0 变为 1
Now because the exp field is nonzero
现在因为 exp 域非全零
This is no longer a denormalized number,It's a normalized number
这不再是非规格化的值，而是一个规格化数字
Okay so now we're changing the definition of E from 1-bias to exp - bias
好的，现在我们将 E 的定义从 1-bias 改为 Exp-bias
So what's exp in this case ?
那么在这种情况下指数字段 exp 是什么？
1-7,the bias is -6
1-7，偏置为 -6
So lower in hold,it's the same exponent as the previous denormalized number
因此指数保持不变，它与先前非规格化值的指数相同
So this is actually very clever by the IEEE folks
所以说 IEEE 的家伙们实际上非常聪明
Because you get the spirit,you get this nice smooth transition from denorm to normalize
因为你领略了其中的精髓，你会明白从非规格化数到规格化数的平滑过渡
So you can see that our exponent E is -6 still
所以你可以看到我们的指数 E 仍为 -6
And now,because we're taking 1-bias(7) And are significant now remember this is a normalized number
现在，因为我们正在使用 1-bias（7），记住这是一个规格化的数字
Because the exp field is nonzero
因为 exp 域非全零
They are a frac field of all zeros represents a significant of 1.000
值得注意的是，小数字段全 0 代表 1.000
Okay so this normalized number this the smallest normalized number
好的，这个标准化的数字是最小的标准化数字
Represents is 1.000 which is 8/8*2^-6(1/64) which gives us 8/512
代表是 1.000，这是 8/8*2^-6（1/64），它给我们 8/512
So we've made this nice smooth transition from 7/512 to 8/512
所以我们已经实现了从 7/512 到 8/512 的平滑过渡
And how do one more
下一个该如何进行呢
I don't want to
我其实不枚举了:)
So if we bump keeping the exp field 1
我们让exp值继续为1
If we bump our frac field from 0 to 1
如果我们将我们的 frac 从 0 增加到 1
Now this represents the the significant of 1.001
这表示1.001（而不是0.001，因为规格化值有隐藏的1）
Which is 8/8+1/8
十进制值是 8/8+1/8
So that's 9/8 times...and then the value is 9/8*2^-6(1/64) which is equal to 9/512
最终值为 9/8*2^-6（1/64），等于 9/512
Okay
好的
Any questions about that?
对此有任何疑问？
Question back here
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Okay the question is why do you choose the bias that to be 2^(k-1) - 1
好的问题是为什么你选择偏置值为 2^(k-1)-1
Well go back to my finger diagram here
那么回到我的手指图
so this is the range of exp fields that you want to
所以这是你想要的 exp 域的范围
This is the range of E that you want to represent with 0 in the middle
你希望 E 范围的中位数是 0
Okay and so you want to bias
所以你需要进行偏置
So that this is halfway，the smallest exponent is halfway to 0
这是E范围的一半的，最小的指数和0距离为E范围的一半
So you want the bias to shift it up
所以你希望偏置值能够改变它
So it's the smallest value of exp corresponds to the smallest exponent
因此，exp 的最小值对应于最小的指数
Right so 2^(k-1)-1 is just giving you a value that's halfway between the smallest exponent and the largest exponent
对，所以 2^(k-1)-1 只给你一个在最小指数和最大指数之间的值
Okay
好的
That's good.Any other questions?
这个问题很棒。还有其他问题吗？
Okay if we take a little smaller six bit format same thing as we did before
好的，如果我们采用与之前相同的六位格式
Just different numbers of bits in exp and frac
exp 和 frac 有不同的位数
And then we plot these on the number line
然后我们在数轴上绘制这些图
You can see that the values are very dense around zero
你可以看到值在零附近非常密集
So they're very spaced very closely together
所以他们非常紧密地在一起
And then every time you increase the exponent by one
然后每次将指数增加一
The numbers are spaced twice as far apart as the previous
这些数字的距离是前一个的两倍
The numbers that were represented by the previous exponent
由前一个指数表示的数字
So you can see like in this little example
所以你可以在这个小例子中看到
You see these...these values here are all equally spaced
你看到这些......这里的这些值都是等间距的
These four values are equally spaced and they're right next to each other
这四个值间隔相等，它们彼此相邻
And then you see this jump in the spacing that represents an increase in the exp field by one
你会看到这些值之间是有间隔的，表示 exp 域增加了 1
And then that spacing doubles as we go out
然后，随着点向外扩展，间距加倍
And you can see it even better here this if we zoom in
如果我们放大，你可以更清楚的看到它
These blue values or denorms
这些蓝色值或非规格化值
And then we have the the next set of normalized values where the frac field is 1
然后我们得到下一组规格化值，其中 frac 为 1
They're spaced the same right we saw this when we kept increasing by 1/512
当我们不停的增加 1/512 时，它们与我们看到的相同
And then we increase the the exponent by one and the spacing doubles
然后我们将指数增加 1，间距增加一倍
Okay so this like I mentioned this encoding has some pretty nice properties
好的，所以这就像我提到的这个编码有一些非常好的属性
The floating point zero  is encoded as integer zero which is nice
浮点零被编码为整数零
And with the exception of not a number,with the exception of not a number
除了非数字之外
You can compare any floating-point numbers
你可以比较任何浮点数
Including infinity by just treating it as doing an unsigned comparison
通过将其视为无符号比较来包括无穷大
So that's really nice too
所以这也很好
Um now if you, when you add and multiply floating point numbers
嗯，当你对浮点数进行相加或相乘操作时
Right we're dealing with a limited set of bits here
对，我们在这里处理一组有限的位
So if we take two numbers encoded as floating-point
所以如果我们把两个数字编码为浮点数
And we add them together there's no guarantee that we'll be able to fit all those bits
两个数加在一起并不能保证结果能用这些有限位表示
In the bits we have available to us
我们有限的位
There's no guarantee that we'll be able to fit the the bits and the result
不能保证结果能用这些有限位表示
So what we do in this case is
所以我们在这种情况下做的是
You can imagine the model you want to have a floating-point operations addition to multiplication
浮点数加法你可以类比成乘法
It's that you add or multiply you do the addition or multiplication
你自己做加法或乘法
And you compute the exact result
然后你计算出确切的结果
You just assume that you have an infinite amount of number of bits
你只是假设你拥有无限数量的位数
And then you round use the technique called rounding to get it to fit into the of the available bits
然后你使用称为舍入的技术使有限的位数能够表示
So the the effect
所以效果是
Is like you doing say x + y is getting the precise value of x + y at an infinite number of bits
就像你说的那样，x + y 在无穷多的位数上得到 x + y 的精确值
And then rounding into the available bits
然后四舍五入到可用位
So let's look at this idea of rounding
那么让我们来看看这种舍入的想法
This can be confusing the first you see it requires
一开始你可能会感到困惑
You need to think about it carefully to get it right
你需要认真思考才能想明白
Now in IEEE there's four different kinds of rounding
现在在 IEEE 中有四种不同的舍入方式
There's round towards zero, round down route or round to minus infinity, Round up to which is rounding it to positive infinity
有向零舍入，向下舍入，向上舍入
And then the default case
然后是默认情况
Which is the only one route we're really going to consider
这是我们唯一一种需要去思考的方式
Which is round to the nearest even
也就是向偶数舍入
And this is what IEEE does by default
这就是 IEEE 制定的默认舍入规则
You can,you can...
你可以，你可以......
If you go into assembly language you can change the rounding
如果使用汇编语言，则可以更改舍入
But we're not going to consider it any more.Yes question
但我们不会再考虑它了。好的，请提问
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
I'm sorry
抱歉
There is right because there's one
是的，因为有一个
So the question is there a distinct negative infinity and a distinct positive infinity
所以问题是存在独特的负无穷大和独特的正无穷大
And there is they have the exact same bit representation except the most significant bit for negative infinity is one
并且它们具有完全相同的位表示，除了负无穷大的符号位是 1
And for positive infinity it's zero
对于正无穷大，它是零
Yes question
请提问
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Why is nearest even?
为什么距离最近？
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Oh I'll show you,let me go over the others
哦，我会告诉你，让我们听听别人的问题
The question was about nearest even.yes
问题是关于最近的偶数。请继续
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Well that was the exception right
那是例外
That's right so aside from infinity you can't do that comparison
这是正确的，除了无限大之外你不能做那种比较
Positive infinity works right but not negative so you're right
正无穷有效，负无穷不可以，所以你是对的
But good point
但这是个好问题
Let's look at these rounding modes and i'll explain why the neuro steven works
让我们看看这些舍入模式，我将解释这些舍入模式的原理
But let's look at so rounding towards zero what we're going to do
但是让我们看看向零舍入，我们要做些什么
We'll use dollars,so we want to round to the nearest dollar
我们将使用美元举例，因此我们希望舍入到最接近的美元
Towards zero just anything less than you just round towards zero
向零舍入，不到 1 你就舍去为 0
So dollar forty would go to one
所以 1.4 美元会变成 1 美元
A dollar sixty would go down to one
1.60 美元将舍为 1 美元
A dollar fifty to one
1.50 美元舍为 1 美元
Two fifty would go to two
2.50 美元会舍为 2 美元
-1.50 you round towards zero
-1.50 你向零舍入
So that would be negative one
所以这将是 -1 美元
Round down or towards negative infinity It's similar the only difference is that for negative one point
向下舍入或朝向负无穷大舍入类似，唯一的区别是 -1.50
-1.50 you drown towards negative infinity which would be -2
-1.50 你趋向负无穷大，即 -2
Rounding up is symmetric to round down
向上舍入和向下舍入正好相反
The interesting case is round to nearest even
有趣的情况是向偶数舍入
Interesting because it's what IEEE floating point actually uses
因为它是 IEEE 浮点实际使用的舍入方式
So the idea here if you have a value that's less than half  then you round down
所以这里的想法是，如果你的值小于一半，那么你向下舍入
If you have a value that's more than halfway between two dollar amounts you round up
如果你的值超过两美元的一半，那么你就会向上舍入
The route that nearest even part comes when you have something that's exactly halfway
向偶数舍入可以区分正好在中间的部分
Then what you do is you round towards the nearest even number
然后你要做的是你向最近的偶数舍入
Okay so in this example a dollar forty
好的，在这个例子中 1.40 美元
Because it's less than half rounds down to one dollar
因为它不到一半舍入到一美元
A dollar sixty is greater than half so we round up to two dollars
1.60 美元大于一半，所以舍入为 2 美元
A dollar fifty right in the middle we round up to the nearest even
1.50 美元我们四舍五入到最近的偶数
Dollar amount which is two dollars
也就是舍入到两美元
Two dollars and fifty cents we round down to the nearest even
2.5 美元我们向下舍入到最近的偶数
Right if we round it up it would be three which is it odd number
对，如果我们将它向上舍入，那就是 3 美元，这是奇数
And minus a dollar fifty we round two we round down to minus two dollars
我们 -1.5 美元，我们向下舍入到 -2 美元
So the reason we do this the reason they chose this is that statistically
我们这样做是有统计学的理由的
If you would imagine
如果你想象一下
If you have a uniform distribution of sort of numbers
如果你有一组均匀分布的数据
They're going to round up or down about 50% of the times
他们将有 50% 的几率向上或向下取整
So there won't be a statistical bias rounding up or down one way or the other
因此，不存在平均值偏大或平均值偏小的统计偏差
So that's the reason they did that
所以这就是他们这样做的原因
Now you can apply this you can do this rounding to any value
现在你可以应用此功能，你可以将此舍入到任何值
So in the last example we did it to the nearest dollar
所以在最后一个例子中，我们得到了最接近的美元
But let's suppose we wanted to round to the nearest hundredth using round to even
但是我们假设我们想要使用向偶数舍入的方法舍入到百分之一
The default round to even mode
使用默认的二进制向偶数舍入
So we want to round to the the nearest hundredth is this second position this
我们想要舍入到百分位
First do we have tenths then hundreds
首先，我们有十分位，然后是百分位
So if we have a value 7.8949999
所以，如果我们有一个值 7.8949999
That's less than halfway
千分位还不到一半
Halfway would be any number that had a five followed by all zeros
中间数（halfway）是任何一个 5 后跟全零的数字（7.50，7.645000，6.345000 等）
So 49999 is less than that
所以 49999 不到一半
So we would just round down to 7.89
所以我们只需要向下舍入到 7.89
Even though 9 is odd
即使 9 是奇数
The only time we're going to apply round to even is when we're exactly halfway
只有当某个数是中间数时我们才会使用向偶数舍入
Okay our next example 7.895001that's greater than halfway
好的，我们的下一个例子 7.895001 大于一半
Right if this was a zero it would be exactly halfway so we round up to 7.9
如果最后一位不是 1 而是 0 的话，那么它就是一个中间数，但现在它不是，所以我们将其舍入为 7.90
Here's the interesting case where we have 7.895 followed by all zeroes that's exactly halfway
这是一个有趣的案例，我们有 7.895，后面全是零，正好是一半
So now we apply the round to nearest even rule
所以现在我们将应用舍入到最近的偶数规则
Nine is an odd number so that doesn't work so we round up
九是一个奇数，所以我们向上舍入
And we do that basically by adding a five here
我们基本上通过在这里添加一个 5 来做到这一点
So five and five is ten and then that carries over
所以五加五是十，然后继续
To the next position and nine and one is zero, nine and one is 10,so that carries over
到下一个位置，九和一是零，九和一是 10，所以继续
And so 8+1=9,so the result is set of rounding up is 7.90
所以 8+1=9，所以结果集合为 7.90
Okay is that clear do you see
好的，你看得清楚吗？
There's a very mechanical way when you round up
当你向上舍入时，有一种非常固定的方式
It's always it's a very mechanical like that
方法很固定
You always just add the half-way number in this case five
在这种情况下，你只需添加中间数字五
And then just propagate it out just do the addition and that will give you the nearest
然后只需进行相加，这将给你最近的结果
The nearest that will round you up to the nearest hundredth in this case
在这种情况下，将得到最接近的百分位
Okay now the last case 7.885 followed by all zeros
好的，现在是最后一个案例7.885，后面是全零
That's another number that's halfway between two numbers rounded to the nearest hundredth
这是另一个两个数字中间的数字，四舍五入到最接近的百分位
So in this case eight is even
所以在这种情况下，八是偶数
So we just we round down and to round down we just truncate
所以我们只是向下舍入
Just throw these bits these these digits away and we get 7.88
把这些数字丢掉，我们得到7.88
So there any questions about this
所以对此有任何疑问
Question back here yes
现在来回答疑问
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Yes that's... so the question was
是的，所以问题是......
Numbers that have the same exp field
具有相同 exp 域的数字
Will those numbers be equally spaced on the number line and the answer is yes
这些数字在数轴上是否相等，答案是肯定的
Yes question
请讲
[student question]
[学生问题]
It would round up
它会向上舍入
Yeah the only,the half way values are always in this case because it's base 10
是的，在这种情况下，中间值始终会向上舍入因为基数是 10
The the half way number in base 10 is 5
基数 10 的中间数是 5
And then it's always the half way number in this case 5 followed by all zeroes
在这种情况下中间数就是 5 后面跟是 0 的数
You'll always have that the half way, if a value is halfway between  like 200 it'll always have that form
这种计算中间值的方法总是有效的
Alright now we can do the same thing with binary fractional numbers as well
好了，现在我们也可以用二进制小数进行相同的操作
Now a binary number is even
现在二进制数是偶数
If the least significant digit is 0
如果最低有效位为 0（它是偶数）
Ok we only have 2 digits right so odd is 1 and 0 is even
好的，我们只有 2 位数，所以奇数是 1，0 是偶数
And the halfway,so the halfway value is going to be a 1 followed by all zeros
（二进制情况下）中间数是 1 后面全为 0 的
Ok that represents exactly halfway
这就是二进制情况下的中间数
So it's analogous to the base 10 example
所以它类似于基数 10
Except where the halfway value is going to be one followed by all zeros
除了（二进制下）中间数是 1 后面全部为 0
So let's look at some examples
那么让我们看看一些例子
So suppose we have, we want to represent 2 3/32
假设我们想表示 2 3/32（假分数，二又三十二分之三）
And suppose we only have four bits to do that in
假设我们只有四个有效位
Okay well to represent that exact we need seven bits
好的，要精确表示我们需要 7 位
And so we have to round
所以我们必须舍入
Okay so let's look at
好的，让我们来看看
So we're going to round to this two bits right of the binary point
所以我们要舍入到二进制点的后两位
And so let's look at all the bits that follow that
所以让我们看看后面的所有位
So since it starts with zero
因为它从零开始
This is going to be less than halfway
这不到一半
So since it's less than halfway we just truncate
因为它不到一半我们直接舍去
Just chop those out and the result is 10.00
把它们砍掉，结果是 10.00
Now our next example is 10.00110
现在我们的下一个例子是 10.00110
So if we look at these the bits to the right of the  to the right of the the bit we're rounding to
如果我们看一下这些二进制点右侧的位
Since it starts with one and it's not followed by all zeros
因为它从1开始，并没有全部为 0
That's greater than half
这大于一半
So in this case we have to round up and so the way we do that
因此，在这种情况下，我们必须向上舍入
That is, we take one and we add it to this leftmost one right here and
也就是说，我们在最左边的数加 1
Add just do the addition and the result is 10.01
添加后结果为 10.01
Now let's look at 2 7/8
现在让我们来看看 2 7/8
This is represented as 10.11100
这表示为 10.11100
Now here's that halfway marker that we were looking for
这是我们正在寻找的中间值
It's a 1 followed by all 0,so this is exactly halfway
它是 1 跟着全 0，所以这正好是中间值
So now we have to round to the nearest even
所以现在我们必须舍入到最近的偶数
Number now that if we can't just truncate,because then it would be an odd number
我们不能截断，因为那将是一个奇数
Right we would end 10.11 is an odd number
我们将得到的 10.11 是一个奇数
So we have to round up
所以我们必须向上取整
And we do that by adding,we do that by adding a 1
我们通过添加 1 来实现
Right here it is to this less leftmost red bit,we add one to that And then just do the addition
就在这里，我们在红色位左边的位上加 1
And we end up with 11.00 which is 3
我们最终得到 11.00 即 3
So the nearest value to 2 7/8
所以离 2 7/8 最近的值
The nearest rounded value is that is 3
最接近的舍入值是 3
Okay last example 2 5/8
好的，最后一个例子 2 5/8
We have the same halfway marker again 100
我们又发现了中位数的标记 100
But in this case the hundredths bit
但在这种情况下，百分位上的点
Are the 1/4 bit is 0
1/4 位是为 0
So that's even,so we can just truncate we just throw those bits away
所以这是偶数，所以我们可以截断后边的位
And the result is simply 10.10
结果就是 10.10
It makes sense
就是这样
So it's very mechanical mainly you just need to be able to recognize that halfway marker
所以它的方法非常固定，你只需要能够识别中间值
And then figure out if you need to round up or down
然后弄清楚你是否需要向上或向下舍入
If you're going to round down just truncate
如果你要向下舍入只是截断
If you're going to round up add a 1 and just propagate it to get your result
如果你打算向上舍入添加 1 并进位以获得结果
Okay now we won't spend much time
好的，现在我们不会花太多时间
I just want to mention a few things about multiplication in addition
我只想提一下有关乘法的一些事情
So if we multiply two numbers
所以，如果我们将两个数字相乘
So we have different mantises significance and exponents
这两个数字有不同的符号位和指数
And suppose that the result is m*2^e
假设结果是 m*2^E
The sign bit will be the xor of the two sign bits of the two operands
符号位将是两个操作数的符号位的异或值
The significant m will be the multiplying m1*m2
显然尾数 m 是 m1*m2
And the exponents are added right
并且结果的指数是两个操作数指数之和
Because they just missed by the rules of exponents
因为他们仅仅只是没有满足指数的规则
So if m >= 2 and this is a normalized number
所以如果 m>=2，这是一个标准化的数字
We have to put it in the range between 1 and 2 by shifting to the right and incrementing the exponent
我们需要向右移位同时增加指数来让尾数在 1 和 2 的范围内
If e is out of range then we overflow 2 to infinity
如果指数 E 超出范围，那么我们将溢出到无穷大
And then if m has too many bits we have to use round to even
然后，如果 M 有太多位，我们必须使用向偶数舍入的方法进行四舍五入
To fit it into the available fragments
让有限的尾数位能够表示
Ok addition,so suppose we're trying to add two floating point numbers
好的，另外，假设我们正在尝试相加两个浮点数
Conceptually what you do is think of those numbers as fractional binary numbers
从概念上讲，你所做的就是将这些数字视为二进制小数
You want to line up the binary points and then do the addition and then normalize the number
你想先对齐二进制小数点，然后相加，接着对数字进行规格化
So that the normalized the significand so it's between 1 & 2
将有效数字规格化，使其在 1 和 2 之间
And either do that by shifting right or left
可以通过向右或向左移动来做到这一点
If e is too big then you overflow
如果 E 太大，那么你就溢出了
And then you round the the bits and m to fit into the available frac field
然后对 M 进行舍入操作以满足 frac 域位数的限制
Now remember when we the first day of class
现在回忆下我们第一天上的课
We talked about what you call these great realities
我们谈到了你们所说的这些伟大的现实
That ints aren't really integers and floats aren't really reals
那个整数并不是真正的整数，浮点数也不是真的
Just as we saw when we looked at two's complement representation of integers
正如我们在学习二进制补码表示时所理解的那样
It's not exactly,they're not exactly like real integers
它们并不是真正的整数
And operations on them aren't exactly like real integers
对它们的操作并不像真正的整数那样
But they follow very predictable mathematical properties
但它们遵循可预测很强的数学特性
Okay that are similar to integers but not quite
它与整数相似，但不完全相同
So the same thing holds for floating-point numbers
浮点数也是如此
They follow very predictable
它们可预测性很强
They have very predictable mathematical properties
它们具有可预测性很强的数学特性
But they're somewhat different from the reals
但它们与实际情况有些不同
And the big thing is that
最重要的是
The big thing with addition is that it doesn't associate
浮点数加法有一个重要问题，那就是它不具有结合性
Okay it's commutative but it's not associative
它是可交换的，但是不可结合
And this usually happens when you're dealing with numbers  that have very large dynamic ranges
当你处理的数字可以在很大范围内变化时，通常会发生这种情况
So if you're trying to add and subtract really big numbers with really little numbers
所以，如果你试图对非常小的数进行加减非常大的数的操作
You run into this this problem of non associativity
你就会遇到不可结合的问题
So the example was if we take 3.14 +  2^10
举个例子，比如 3.14+2^10
2^10 is so much larger than 3.14
2^10 比 3.14 大得多
That when we ,the bits that would be 2^10 + 3.14
如果这些位代表 2^10 + 3.14
The the bits that represent the 3.14
有一些位用来表示 3.14
You know there's bits way out here that represent
你已经知道表示的方式了
There's one bit out here that represents 2^10
有一些位表示 2^10
Then there's a few bits here they represent 3.14
还需要有一些位代表 3.14
And there's just not enough we don't have enough bits to represent all those
我们没有足够的位来表示
So we have the 3.14 goes away
所以 3.14 就消失了
So adding a big number to a little number essentially gives the big number
因此，将一个大数字添加到一个小数字基本上得出了大数字
And then if you subtract that big number you get zero
然后，如果你减去那个大数字就会得到零
Now if we change the the associate
现在，如果我们改变了结合
If we take this big number and subtract it from itself we get zero
如果我们取这个大数并从中减去它，我们就得零
And then,so the result will be instead of zero as before we get 3.14
然后，结果将变为 3.14，而不是之前我们得到的 0
So other than that you you have all of the things that you would normally expect closed
除此之外，浮点运算拥有所有预期的特性
under addition it's commutative there's a additive identity of zero
在加法中，它是可交换的
Except for infinities and nan's there's an additive inverse
浮点数一般都有逆元（除了无穷大和非数字）
You can take for any number there's
你可以使用任何数字
There's an inverse that will give you zero when you add it together and you get monotonicity
有一个相反数使两个数相加为 0，浮点数也满足单调性
Monotonicity between values except of course for infinities and ends
值之间的单调性直到无穷大结束
Now multiplication has... it's similar
乘法也有类似的特性
You get it's closed generally under multiplication it's commutative
一般情况下，乘法是可交换的
But it's not associative and it doesn't distribute over addition
但它不满足结合律，浮点乘法在加法上不满足分配律
And it's the same,so here you can see we're taking 1e^20*1e^20*1e^20 and then so that gives infinity
而且它（和浮点数加法）是一样的，（1e^20*1e^20)*1e^-20 结果是无穷大
But if we reassociate and we take...i
但如果我们重新结合，我们会......
I'm sorry to to the (1e20*1e20)*1e-20
不好意思，对于（1e20*1e20)*1e-20
Well this first multiplication is infinity
第一个括号里面的结果是无穷大
And anything you do with infinity is just infinity so the result is infinity
对无穷大做任何操作都是无穷大，所以结果就是无穷大
However if we reassociate and 1e^20*(1e^20*1e^-20)
但如果我们重新结合得到 1e^20*(1e^20*1e^-20）
That gives us 1,and then 1e^20 and so we get 1e^20
得到 1，然后乘以 1e^20，所以最终得到 1e^20
So the big takeaway point here is that
所以这里最重要的一点是
A floating point isn't associative
浮点是不满足结合律的
Ok now is that a problem
那么现在有一个问题
It's something you have to be aware of and
你们必须要意识到这个问题
But generally I mean I've done a lot of scientific computing in particular modeling earthquake ground motion in southern California
我做过很多科学计算的相关工作，特别是加利福尼亚州南部的地震带模型
So basically we would we would build models of southern California in the computer
我们主要是在计算机上建立了南加州的（地震带）模型
And then we would shake them
然后我们会在计算机上模拟发生地震的情况
And then we would see how the ground moves in like Los Angeles
然后我们会看到地震，比如洛杉矶
And those that's shaking we used a numerical method called finite elements
在地震中，我们使用了一种称为有限元的数值方法
And it was all it used all floating point single precision floating point numbers
它只使用单精度浮点数
And we never ran into a problem this with this associativity right
我们从来没有因为不满足结合律而遇到问题
We would do operations in different orders
我们会以不同的顺序进行操作
We couldn't always guarantee that we would do the operations in the exact same order
我们不能保会一直以完全相同的顺序进行操作
But we never ran into a problem with this because
但是我们从来没有遇到过这个问题，因为
Nature and generally in general is kind of smooth right that
自然界中的变化通常是连续的
If you look at the,you know if one part of the ground is shaking like this and
如果你看一下，你会知道地面的一部分是否像这样摇晃
You look at the next part it might be shaking a little more or a little less
你看下一部分时它可能会稍微摇晃的多一点或少一点
But you're not going to have like huge differences
但是（数值上）不会产生巨大的差异
And so we never ran into those kind of problems
所以我们从未遇到过这类问题
But in some,so generally if you're simulating natural phenomena
但在某些情况下，如果你在模拟一般的自然现象
You don't often see these kind of huge dynamic ranges
你一般不会遇到这种巨大的变化范围
But other times you know if it's not non natural financial
但有时候是非自然情况，比如金融
Maybe financial systems they use floating point
也许金融系统使用浮点数
Then you might see this larger dynamic the numbers and it might become a problem
然后你可能会看到更大的动态数字，它可能会出现问题
So as a programmer you just generally have to be aware of this
所以作为程序员，你通常必须要注意这一点
You have to have a good sense for the dynamic range of your numbers
你必须要弄明白数字的变化范围
And you have to keep in mind that if you reassociate or change the order of things
而且你必须记住，如果你重新结合或改变运算的顺序
You may not get exactly the same exactly the same answer
你可能无法得到完全相同的答案
Okay now see gives us two different kinds of floating points
现在有两种不同的浮点数
So they the float is the IEEE single precision and double is the IEEE double precision
因此，浮点数是有 IEEE 单精度，和 IEEE 双精度浮点数
Now you remember when we did casting between ints and unsigned values back and forth
现在回想下我们在整数和无符号整数之间进行转换的时候
The cast never changed the bit representation it just changed the way that
转换从未改变过位的表示，只是改变了某些位的解释方式
In fact it never even changed the the be what the a...
事实上，它一直没有改变过......
How the a or you manipulated those bits
你如何操纵这些位
It's really just a how were interpreting and how we're viewing those those values
仅仅只是取决于我们解释和看待那些值的方式
However when you do cast between floats and ints and doubles
但是，当你在单精度浮点数、整数和双精度浮点数之间进行转换时
The bit representation changes
位的表示发生了变化
Right so a cast here has a dramatic effect on the actual bits themselves
对，所以类型转换会对位的值产生实际的影响
Now if we go from a double or a float to an int
现在，如果我们从 double 或 float 转到 int
It's going to truncate the fractional part and give us the
它将截去小数部分
Give us the the integer part and then round to fit
留给我们整数部分
Oh actually no there won't be...
不会进行舍入
Okay so think about this how many there were you said 23 frac bits and float
单精度浮点数的 frac 域有 23 位
And I forget exactly how many in doubles
我忘记了双精度的数量
Doesn't matter it's some number,well no it does matter
只是一些无关紧要的数字，当然（实际上）它很重要
Let's so for a float if we cast a float to an int
如果我们将一个浮点数转换为 int
We're casting 23 something that we can represent with 23 at most 23 frac bits into a 32 bit
我们会将最多用 23 位表示的数用 32 位表示
It so we won't will never lose so we won't we'll never need to do any rounding
所以我们不会丢掉某些位，不需要做任何舍入
But double-precision has 52 bits
但是双精度有 52 位
Okay so there we may not be able to fit the represented integer into the int
好的，我们可能无法将（截去小数部分后的）整数放入 int 中
So they'll have to be some rounding
所以他们必须要进行一些舍入
Sorry powerpoint crashed
抱歉，powerpoint 崩溃了
Okay right now if we cast,if we cast from an int to a double
如果我们把一个 int 转换为 double
There's will have will have enough debt,so we won't lose anything right
有足够的位来表示，所以我们不会丢掉任何东西
The 32 bits will fit in the double precision frac field
双精度浮点数的 frac 放得下 32 位
And but int to float has there's more bits than an int that then there are in the frac field of a float
但是 int 转换为 float 时，int 的位比 floa t的 frac 域位数多
So we'll have to do some rounding right so the
所以我们必须做一些舍入
So casting works the same way as any other operation
转换方式与其他操作相同
You can think of it as just taking the assume you have an infinite number of bits
你可以假设你拥有无限数量的位
Get the exact result and then round it to fit into the available bits
得到确切的结果，然后将其舍入到可用位
All right so let's the final thing I want to do today is Sort of test your understanding do solve some puzzles to test
我们今天要做的最后一件事就是看一下你们的理解程度，我们通过解决一些题目来测试一下
Test our understanding of these properties of floating-point numbers
测试我们对浮点数的这些属性的理解
So imagine that we have three values x as an int, f is a float and d is a double
所以假设我们有三个值，x是int类型，f是浮点数类型，d是double类型
And then we're evaluating the c, c expressions
然后我们来判断下面的c语言表达式
So x is, x == (int)(float) x
所以 x ==  (int)(float)x 真值是 1 吗
Yeah
是的
How you can edit out the,you can edit out that other stuff
如何编辑出来，你可以编辑出其他东西
Okay all right so what do you think if we...
你觉得如果我们
So if we take x which is an int cast it to a float
如果我们将一个 int 型 x，将它转换为 float
And then cast that back to an int will that always be equal to x
然后将其转换回一个 int，结果等于 x
No
不对
Right as we lose some bits right we don't have enough frac bits in float
我们丢失了一些位，我们在浮点数中 frac 域没有足够的位（来表示 int）
What about if we take x cast it to a double and then cast it back to int
如果我们将 x 转换为 double 然后将其强制转换为 int，结果怎么样？
Well we always get equivalent value yeah
我们肯定能得到相同的值
Because we have enough frac bits and none in double
因为在 double 里 frac 域有位数
Now what if we take a float f,cast it to a double,and then cast it back to a float
现在如果我们采用 floa t型 f，将其转换为 double，然后将其转换回 float
Well that always equal the original f
也会等于原来的 f
Yeah,what about the converse though?
反过来怎么样？
What if we take the double d cast it to a float and cast it back to a double
如果我们将 double d 转换为 float 到并将其转换为 double，结果如何？
No
不相等
How about this, how about if we take f Negate it and then negate that again will that always equal f
如果我们对 f 两次取反还会等于f吗
Yeah because we're just toggling a bit right
答案是肯定的因为我们只是改变了一个位的值（符号位）
Okay how about 2/3 == 2/3.0
2/3==2/3.0 的真值为 1 吗
No because 2/3 is 0
它俩不相等，因为 2/3 是 0
And 2/3.0 is a is a floating point value 2/3 the floating point representation of 2/3
而 2/3.0 是一个浮点数 2/3
Okay how about if the double d is less than 0
那么如果 d<0.0
Does that imply that d*2 is also less than 0?
这是否意味着 d*2 也小于 0？
Yeah even if no matter what even if 2*d overflows
是的即使 2*d 溢出也是这样
It will overflow to negative infinity which is less than,which is less than zero
即使溢出到负无穷大，也是小于零
Okay how about does the double d greater than f imply that -f is greater than -d
如果 double 型的 d 大于 float 型的 f，那么 -f 大于 -d 吗
Yeah that's that monotonicity right and again it's just...yes
答案是肯定的，因为单调性
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
Oh that's a good question I think it'd be a float
哦，这是一个很好的问题，我认为是一个 float
I think if you put there's an annotation and see to to give it a double
我想如果你给它一个注解并将其看成 double
But actually I'd have to check that out that's....enough yeah that's a good question I don't know
但实际上我必须检查那个......这是一个好问题，但是我不知道
We'd have to check after to go and look in the c guide
我们必须实践检验并查看 C 语言指南
How about it is d squared the double d squared always greater than or equal to zero yes
d 的平方总是大于或等于零，这对吗？
And how about does d plus f minus d always equal f
那么 d 加 f 减去 d 总是等于 f 吗？
No because of a lack of associativity
不等于，因为浮点数不满足结合律
Okay so that was that was that was fun right
很有趣
Floating points always fun
浮点数一直很有趣
So anyway that the big thing is just to realize that floats aren't exactly really reals
所以无论如何，一定要意识到 float 不是实际的数
But they have very predictable properties
但它们（运算结果）的可预测很强
And that they're not associative or commutative,they're not associative
而且他们不满足结合律
So you have to be careful about that
所以你必须要小心
All right we'll have a good weekend we'll see you on Tuesday
周末愉快，下周二见